pipspread.com 2018-11-15

# Privacy Policy | PipSpread

August 11, 2018September 17, 2018

Privacy Policy

Rate this post 

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally identifiable information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website. PipSpread is committed to protecting your privacy. This “Privacy Policy” describes how collect, store and use information on individuals that use this Web Site.

#### What personal information do PipSpread collect from the people that visit the blog, website or app?

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address or other details to help you with your experience.

#### When do collect information?

PipSpread collect information from you when user register on the site, fill out a form or enter information on our site.

#### How do PipSpread use your information?

PipSpread may use the information PipSpread collect from users when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To personalize user’s experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.
  * To improve our website in order to better serve you.
  * To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.

#### How do PipSpread protect visitor information?

The website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible. PipSpread use regular Malware Scanning.

PipSpread do not use an SSL certificate. PipSpread only provide articles and information, PipSpread never ask for personal or private information like phone number, or credit card numbers.

#### Do PipSpread use ‘cookies’?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, PipSpread use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. PipSpread also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that PipSpread can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

#### PipSpread use cookies to:

  * Keep track of advertisements.
  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. PipSpread may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you disable cookies off, some features will be disabled It won’t affect the users experience that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly.

#### Third Party Disclosure

PipSpread do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless PipSpread provide you with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. PipSpread may also release your information when PipSpread believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

#### Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, PipSpread may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. PipSpread therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, PipSpread seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

#### Google

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by Google’s Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. <https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en>. Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

#### California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. – See more at: <http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf>

#### According to CalOPPA PipSpread agree to the following:

Users can visit our site anonymously Once this privacy policy is created, PipSpread will add a link to it on the home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website. Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’, and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes on our Privacy Policy Page. Users are able to change their personal information by logging in to their account

#### How does our site handle do not track signals?

PipSpread honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

#### COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation’s consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online. PipSpread does not specifically market to children under 13.

#### Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

#### CAN SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations. PipSpread collect user’s email address in order to send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

To be in accordance with CANSPAM PipSpread agree to the following:

  * NOT use false, or misleading subjects or email addresses
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way
  * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters
  * Monitor third party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email

#### If at any time user would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, the he/she can email us at

[support@pipspread.com](mailto:support@pipspread.com) and PipSpread will promptly remove from ALL correspondence.
